

## Nenette S. Cereza

#13 Cabuco Street Phase 2B Bahayang Pag-asa Molino 5 Bacoor Cavite, Philippines +63 9175125089• nenettecereza@yahoo.com

#### **OBJECTIVE**

To be part of the company's success towards achieving its organizational goal, giving me the opportunity for my personal and professional expansion where I can make full use of my accounting and administrative expertise and continuously improve my skills and knowledge and in return inspire me to be an asset in contributing to the company's triumph thus supporting it's ideals, principles and values. To ensure best practice in financial, human resource and administrative management of the organization in order to maximize efficiency and growth.

#### **SKILLS & QUALIFICATIONS**

- Finance (bookkeeping, financial compliance, ordering and payroll, financial management, credit control, invoicing, financial reporting, and bank reconciliation)
- Administration (corporate compliance procedures, recruitment, time sheet management, systems and database management)
- Human Resources
- Proficient in English and Filipino
- Highly Personable and Ability to Deal with People of Different Backgrounds
- Dedicated and knows how to produce results. Self-driven and assertive, able to work effectively and can easily adapt to changes. Seeks continuous knowledge and competitive in computer industry, hard working, detail oriented and able to do multi-tasking.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE:

## FINANCE MANAGER – iMoney Comparison Philippines Inc. – July 27, 2015 - Present

### **General Responsibilities:**

Provide support to Operations group, through information analyses (e.g. current processes, actual performance vs. budget and prior year, budget, etc.), preparation of operational data/analyses for publication to various constituents throughout company (Management, Sales, Product Management, Operations, etc.) who rely on/benefit from the information to make informed business decisions. Primary responsibilities will include assisting Operations team in the Monthly Operations Review, identification of areas for cost reductions and operational improvements, annual budget process, periodic forecasting, and periodic analysis of operations performance.

## **Specific Responsibilities:**

Oversee the overall corporate budgeting preparation, management and monitoring processes.

Perform financial analysis, reporting and management activities.

Ensure that the financial reports are prepared and delivered on time.

Review financial data for accuracy, correctness and completeness.

Hire and train new employees on financial operations.

Monitor and manage all expense within the allotted budget.

Establish key financial strategies to enhance business profitability.

Ensure financial team follows company policies and regulations.

Develop standard accounting procedures to improve financial operations efficiency.

Participate in performance evaluation of finance staff and conduct counseling sessions to identify skill development needs.

Review annual budgets and recommend any changes if needed.

Assist in account payable and receivable activities.

Perform account reconciliation activities.

Generate financial reports related to budgets, account payables, account receivables, expenses, etc.

Ensure accurate calculation and distribution of salaries and other benefits to employees.

Establish accurate forecasts regarding expenses and revenues and manage regular reporting requirements.

Monitor competitor activity and stay updated about latest industry trends.

#### FINANCE & HR MANAGER – aCOMMERCE PHILS. INC. – August 2013 – July 15, 2015

### **General Responsibilities as Finance Manager**

Provide support to Operations group, through information analyses (e.g. current processes, actual performance vs. budget and prior year, budget, etc.), preparation of operational data/analyses for publication to various constituents throughout company (Management, Sales, Product Management, Operations, etc.) who rely on benefit from the information to make informed business decisions. Primary responsibilities will include assisting Operations team in the Monthly Operations Review, identification of areas for cost reductions and operational improvements, annual budget process, periodic forecasting, and periodic analysis of operations performance.

Responsible for the overall good maintenance of accounting books and systems.

Forecast cash flow requirements and, in consultation with the General Manager, request inter-bank transfers to meet cash needs.

Prepare bank reconciliation statements to keep track of balances.

Ensure compliance with organizational financial policy as well as statutory financial requirements.

In collaboration with the Internal Auditor, I will make recommendations for update of financial policy and procedures as necessary.

#### **General Responsibilities as HR Manager**

Corporate Compliance Procedure ( to provide an in-house compliance service that effectively supports business areas in their duty to comply with relevant laws and regulations and internal procedures).

Maintain and review from time to time job descriptions for all positions in the organization.

Maintain, implement and review from time to time an annual staff appraisal system and other tools.

Maintain and review from time to time the staff manual for the organization.

Doing the payroll, statutory deductions and other related payments.

In cooperation with the General Manager, pre-sanction and monitor staff loans and control implementation of the staff loan policy.

In cooperation with Heads of Departments & General Manager, pre-approve and monitor leave applications.

In cooperation with the Heads of Departments, coordinate recruitment and promotion processes.

With the help of HR & Administration Officer, address all industrial relations issues.

Ensure that organization's HR rules and regulations are in compliance with local and national regulations.

Perform other relevant duties as and when it is assigned by the Executive and Management committee.

# ACCOUNTANT- KOMLI PHILS. INC. formerly ADMAX NETWORK PHILIPPINES INC., April 25, 2011 – June 2013

- 1.Lead, manage and monitor accounting functions.
- 2. Develop, generate and manage timely accounting reports.
- 3. Ensure reconciliation of Bank accounts and other accounts.
- 4. Monitor general ledger, accounts receivables, accounts payables and other records.
- 5. Generate various analyses and financial reports for the management.
- 6. Monitor and manage the month-end accounting processes.
- 10. Monitor month-end reports, schedules, payments and receipts.
- 11. Payroll

## ACCOUNTING/ADMINISTRATIVE MANAGER: BDSS MEDIA INC. Makati, July 30, 2010 – March 31, 2011

#### **ACCOUNTING MANAGER**

- 1.Lead, manage and monitor accounting functions.
- 2. Develop, generate and manage timely accounting reports.
- 3. Ensure reconciliation of Bank accounts and other accounts.

- 4. Monitor general ledger, accounts receivables, accounts payables and other records.
- 5. Create management tools that effectively monitor accounting processes.
- 6. Preparing balance sheet and budget reports.
- 7. Generate various analyses and financial reports for the management.
- 8. Monitor and manage the month-end accounting processes.
- 9. Manage budgets for departments, projects and grants.
- 10. Monitor month-end reports, schedules, payments and receipts.
- 11. Create and monitor an effective internal audit system.
- 12. Ensure timely completion of audit.
- 13. Manage absenteeism, performance, payroll and other related issues.
- 14. Maintain, update and monitor inventory records.
- 15. Ensure compliance of all accounting processes to that of the organization's goals.

#### ADMINISTRATIVE MANAGER

- Recruitment
- Hiring
- Organizational Development
- Salary and Benefits
- Policy Recommendation
- Team Building
- Leadership
- Employee Relations

- 1. Responsible of scheduling meetings, managing work product and deadlines of subordinates.
- 2. Duties also pertain to answering interoffice queries and communicating all operational data to management section.
- 3. Provides support to other departments of the organization and organizes projects of the company.
- 4. Responsible of reviewing office budget and managing office expenditure.
- 5. Training staffs and evaluating their performance as they participate towards the growth of the organization.
- 6. Analyzes the attendance and regularity of the working staff of the organization.

# ACCOUNTING HEAD/ADMINISTRATOR: POWERCONNEX, Inc Makati, May 2006- May 20, 2010

- Financial data entry
- Financial reporting
- Cash management
- Administration duties
- Office administration

## **Bookkeeper Duties and Responsibilities:**

- 1. Full cycle of accounting functions, bank reconciliation, preparation of monthly and year end profit and loss account, full cycle of accounts payable, preparation of payrolls, accounts receivable, cash management banking and cash flow management, monitor bank account daily and prepare cash position.
- 2. Monitor the availability of cash to ensure continuing operations, ensuring that all funds are properly deposited in their designated depository.
- 3. Prepares monthly, quarterly reports of the corporation and ensures their accuracy and timeliness.
- 4. Prepare of annual budgets and cash flow projections.
- 5. Review all receipts and disbursements, ascertains correct account distribution and ensuring all support documentation is accurate and in order.
- 6. Perform additional duties as requested by the president of the company.

## **Administrator Duties and Responsibilities:**

- 1. Responsibility for planning, organizing, recruiting, staffing evaluation and assessment.
- 2. Develops and communicates human resources policies and procedures, directing the development of valid and reliable instruments to be used as a basis for fair and legal section, training, performance evaluations, compensation, staff development practices and perform other duties as assigned by the president.

## ACCOUNTING ASSISTANT: ROUNDTREE MERCHANDISING CORP. Feb. 2001 – May 2006

- Payables
- Bookkeeping
- Government Requirements (SSS, Philhealth, BIR, Pag-ibig)
- Receivables
- Payroll

### **Duties and Responsibilities:**

- 1. Prepare, record and process accounts payable and cash disbursements.
- 2. Prepare, record and process accounts receivable and cash receipts.
- 3. Prepare allocations tables for indirect expenses and revenue items as needed.
- 4. Perform monthly bank reconciliations.
- 5. Prepare and process payroll and deductions schedules.
- 6. Posting of accounts to the general ledger, accounts receivable, cash receipts, accounts payable, cash disbursements and payroll.
- 7. Review open invoice reports, follow up with schedule of payments or adjustments.
- 8. Maintain required records, reports, and files in an organized manner.

### PRPOPERTY CUSTODIAN: SINCLAIR PHILIPPINES INC. 1992 - 2001

- Payables
- Company Insurance
- Inventories
- Bookkeeping
- Payroll
- Government Requirements

**Duties and Responsibilities:** 

1. Responsible for the proper record maintenance and safekeeping of the property in its possession.

2. To maintain records on all capital and controlled assets.

3. Responsible for signing authorizations to transfer equipment to other departments, remove property from department inventory such as lost, stolen, or surplus property.

4. Cover the insurance all company property.

5. Managing the accounts payable process from matching purchase orders to invoices through final payment.

6. Prepare and process payroll.

7. Prepare all the payments for government

8. Inspects items for conformance with specifications.

9. Conducts inventories and maintains inventory records and reports.

10. Supervise and trains subordinate personnel and edits requisitions and purchase orders.

11. Confers with department heads, vendors and outside agencies concerning purchases, deliveries and acceptability of supplies.

12. Perform other related duties as directed by my superior.

#### **EDUCATION**

Tertiary Level: 1989 - 1992 Polytecnic University of the Philippines Bachelor of Accountancy

#### CHARACTER REFERENCE

Available upon request